<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<recipes>
<recipe>
<src>http://www.tarladalal.com/members/9306/images/kadai_paneer-2520.jpg</src>
<name>Kadai Paneer</name>
<ingredients>
500 gms (1 1/8 lb.) paneer (cottage cheese)
100 gms capsicum
2 tsp coriander (dhania) seeds
5 whole red chillies
3/4 tsp dried fenugreek leaves (kasuri methi)
2 green chillies, chopped
2 tsp chopped ginger
4 tomatoes, chopped
2 tbsp chopped coriander (dhania)
3 tbsp ghee
salt to taste

For the paste
6 cloves garlic (lehsun) mixed with a little water
</ingredients>
<directions>
<br>1. Slice the paneer and capsicum into thin long strips.</br>
<br>2. Pound the coriander seeds and red chillies together.</br>
<br>3. Heat the ghee, add the garlic paste and cook on a slow flame for a few seconds.</br>
<br>4. Add the capsicum and pounded spices and cook on a slow flame for 30 seconds.</br>
<br>5. Add the green chillies and ginger and fry again for a few seconds.</br>
<br>6. Add the tomatoes and cook until the ghee comes on top.</br>
<br>7. Add the kasoori methi and salt and fry again for a few seconds.</br>
<br>8. Finally, add the sliced paneer and cook for a few minutes.</br>
<br>9. Sprinkle coriander on top and serve hot.</br>
</directions>

</recipe>
<recipe>
<src>http://www.tarladalal.com/members/9306/images/aam-aur-chane-ka-achaar-848.jpg</src>
<name>Aam aur Chane ka Achaar</name>
<ingredients>
1/2 cup kabuli chana (white chick peas)
1 1/2 cups grated raw mango
1 tsp turmeric powder (haldi)
1 tbsp fenugreek (methi) seeds
1 tbsp fenugreek seeds (methi) powder
1 tbsp fennel seeds (saunf)
1/2 tsp asafoetida (hing)
1 tsp nigella seeds (kalonji)
14 whole dry kashmiri red chillies
1 tbsp chilli powder
1 1/4 cups mustard (rai / sarson) oil
1 tbsp salt
</ingredients>
<directions>
<br>Combine the grated mango, turmeric powder and salt and leave aside for 30 minutes.</br>
<br>Squeeze out all the mango water using a muslim cloth and keep aside. Keep the grated mango aside separately.</br>
<br>Soak the Kabuli chana and fenugreek seeds in the mango water overnight.</br>
<br>Refrigerate the grated mango.</br>
<br>Combine the fenugreek seeds powder, fennel seeds, asafoetida, nigella seeds, whole red chillies, chilli powder and soaked Kabuli chana mixture with the grated mango. Mix well.</br>
<br>Heat the mustard oil. Cool it and add to the prepared mixture.</br>
<br>Bottle the pickle in a sterilised glass jar.</br>
<br>The pickle is ready to eat after 3 to 4 days.</br>
<br>Store it a cool dry place for upto 1 year.</br>
</directions>

</recipe>

<recipe>
<src>http://www.tarladalal.com/members/9306/images/bajra-khichdi-(-rajasthani-recipe)-978.jpg</src>
<name>Bajra Khichdi ( Rajasthani Recipe)</name>
<ingredients>
1/3 cup whole bajra (black millet)
3 tbsp yellow moong dal (split yellow gram)
1 tsp cumin seeds (jeera)
1/2 tsp asafoetida (hing)
2 tbsp ghee
salt to taste
</ingredients>
<directions>
<br>Clean and grind the bajra to a coarse powder in a blender. Keep aside.</br>
<br>Wash the ground bajra and moong dal together.</br>
<br>Combine the bajra-moong dal mixture and salt with 2 cups of water and pressure cook for 4 whistles or until the bajra is cooked.</br>
<br>Heat the ghee in a pan and add the cumin seeds and asafoetida. When the seeds crackle, pour this mixture over the cooked khichdi and mix well.</br>
<br>Adjust the consistency of the khichdi at the time of serving by adding ½ cup of hot water if necessary.</br>
<br>Serve hot with ghee, kadhi or curds.</br>

</directions>

</recipe>

<recipe>
<src>http://www.tarladalal.com/members/9306/images/anjeer_basundi-3084.jpg</src>
<name>Anjeer Basundi</name>
<ingredients>
4 cups low fat milk
1 1/2 cups finely chopped fresh figs(anjeer)
1/2 tsp lemon juice
1 tsp cornflour dissolved in 1 tbsp low fat milk
1/2 cup low fat mava (khoya)
2 tbsp sugar substitute
</ingredients>
<directions>
<br>Refrigerate the fig pieces to chill.</br>
<br>Wash the ground bajra and moong dal together.</br>
<br>Pour the milk into a broad non-stick pan and bring to a boil. Simmer over a medium flame stirring continuously.</br>
<br>Add the lemon juice drop by drop to the milk stirring continuously. You will see tiny curdled particles, which are required for the grainy texture of basundi. Do not add the lemon juice all at once, if you do so the milk may curdle completely.</br>
<br>You will get bigger curdled particles which is not desirable.</br>
<br>Add the cornflour mixture, khoya and sugar substitute and mix well and simmer for another 1 to 2 minutes.</br>
<br>Cool and refrigerate for at least 1 hour.</br>
<br>Add the chilled fig pieces to the cooled thickened milk and mix well.</br>
<br>Serve chilled garnished with fig slices.</br>


</directions>

</recipe>


</recipes>